let question_list = [

{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'A ___ occupancy type must meet the building code for its intended use.', 'a': 'a. separated use', 'b': 'b. single-use', 'c': 'c. Type I', 'd': 'd. Type III', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: single-use'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following metals will be affected by heat more rapidly than steel?', 'a': 'a. Lead', 'b': 'b. Aluminum', 'c': 'c. Tin', 'd': 'd. Copper', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Aluminum'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'In what fire stage is structural collapse very likely?', 'a': 'a. Growth', 'b': 'b. Decay', 'c': 'c. Fully developed', 'd': 'd. Incipient', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Decay'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'The International Building Code IBC© and National Fire Protection Association NFPA® define construction type based on the performance of the construction when:', 'a': 'a. exposed to an earthquake.', 'b': 'b. a sprinkler system is activated.', 'c': 'c. exposed to fire.', 'd': 'd. a fire alarm system is activated.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: exposed to fire.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of door protects openings in fire-rate walls?', 'a': 'a. Fire door', 'b': 'b. Hollow-core door', 'c': 'c. Metal door', 'd': 'd. Solid-core door', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fire door'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What occupancy type contains multiple occupancy or use groups?', 'a': 'a. Type III', 'b': 'b. Single-use', 'c': 'c. Separated use', 'd': 'd. Type I', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Separated use'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes when structural collapse may occur?', 'a': 'a. It can only occur before fire suppression.', 'b': 'b. It can occur when all the factors are met.', 'c': 'c. It can occur well after the fire is extinguished.', 'd': 'd. It can only occur during fire suppression.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: It can occur well after the fire is extinguished.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'In what construction type are exterior load-bearing walls composed entirely of wood?', 'a': 'a. Type V', 'b': 'b. Type I', 'c': 'c. Type IV', 'd': 'd. Type III', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Type V'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'According to the National Building Code of Canada NBCC heavy timber construction avoids:', 'a': 'a. using noncombustible materials.', 'b': 'b. concealed spaces under floors and roofs.', 'c': 'c. using flame-retardant materials.', 'd': 'd. having open crawl spaces.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: concealed spaces under floors and roofs.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Laminated timber, medium density fiberboard MDF, and finger-jointed timber are all examples of what common building material?', 'a': 'a. Lath and plaster', 'b': 'b. Metal', 'c': 'c. Plastic', 'd': 'd. Composite material', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Composite material'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of door design can prevent movement of hose or equipment into a building?', 'a': 'a. Folding door', 'b': 'b. Sliding door', 'c': 'c. Vertical door', 'd': 'd. Revolving door', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Revolving door'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of stairs uses a ventilation system activated by automatic fire or smoke detection?', 'a': 'a. Access stairs', 'b': 'b. Smokeproof stair enclosures', 'c': 'c. Fire escapes', 'd': 'd. Protected stairs', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Smokeproof stair enclosures'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Manufactured homes built before 1976 have less ___ than those of current construction:', 'a': 'a. fire resistance', 'b': 'b. lightweight construction', 'c': 'c. building restrictions', 'd': 'd. content load', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: fire resistance'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': "What building component's construction varies depending on its level?", 'a': 'a. Wall', 'b': 'b. Floor/Ceiling', 'c': 'c. Foundation', 'd': 'd. Roof', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Floor/Ceiling'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of roof is used to prevent ice damming?', 'a': 'a. Cold roof', 'b': 'b. Rain roof', 'c': 'c. Green roof', 'd': 'd. Photovoltaic Solar roof', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Cold roof'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Ventilating a rain roof will not remove smoke until:', 'a': 'a. security measures are removed.', 'b': 'b. sheeting layers are pierced.', 'c': 'c. the dead load is mitigated.', 'd': 'd. the original roof is penetrated.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: the original roof is penetrated.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which type of roof is used whenever large open floor spaces with limited interior support is needed?', 'a': 'a. Bowstring truss', 'b': 'b. Lantern', 'c': 'c. Mansard', 'd': 'd. Sawtooth', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Bowstring truss'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'A collapse zone for a Type IV structure should be established when:', 'a': 'a. its veneer begins to curtain collapse.', 'b': 'b. it has been determined that glass shards will be directed at on-scene personnel.', 'c': 'c. the structure has been weakened by repeated fires over time.', 'd': 'd. walls begin to shift because the building is twisting.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: the structure has been weakened by repeated fires over time.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes a primary dangerous building condition?', 'a': 'a. Conditions that permit occupants to safely escape', 'b': 'b. Conditions that allow tactical ventilation', 'c': 'c. Conditions that suppress fire', 'd': 'd. Conditions that contribute to fire spread', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Conditions that contribute to fire spread'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Type III construction requires exterior walls and structural members to be constructed of:', 'a': 'a. large-dimension lumber.', 'b': 'b. noncombustible materials.', 'c': 'c. wood and metal.', 'd': 'd. steel and masonry.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: noncombustible materials.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of door may be required by building codes to be constructed of tempered material that resists breakage?', 'a': 'a. Metal door', 'b': 'b. Fire door', 'c': 'c. Panel door', 'd': 'd. Glass door', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Glass door'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Steel structural members lengthen as much as 4 inches 100 mm when heated to:', 'a': 'a. 500°F 260°C.', 'b': 'b. 900°F 482°C.', 'c': 'c. 1,000°F 538°C.', 'd': 'd. 300°F 149°C.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: 1,000°F 538°C.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Vertical tactical ventilation can be defined as channeling smoke from the:', 'a': 'a. lowest point in a building.', 'b': 'b. point in a building that has the least windows.', 'c': 'c. highest point in a building.', 'd': 'd. point in a building that has the most windows.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: highest point in a building.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What roof type is frequently penetrated by chimneys, shafts and skylights?', 'a': 'a. Arched', 'b': 'b. Flat', 'c': 'c. Shed', 'd': 'd. Pitched', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Flat'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Fuel loading is defined as the maximum heat produced if:', 'a': 'a. no combustible materials are present.', 'b': 'b. all combustible materials in a given area burn.', 'c': 'c. none of the combustible materials in a given area burn.', 'd': 'd. nothing but combustible materials are present.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: all combustible materials in a given area burn.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What part of the roof is exposed to weather?', 'a': 'a. Coverings', 'b': 'b. Penetrations and openings', 'c': 'c. Decks', 'd': 'd. Supports', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Coverings'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': "What part of a roof's construction can be manufactured from smaller pieces of wood or light gauge steel?", 'a': 'a. I-beams', 'b': 'b. Metal gusset plates', 'c': 'c. Box beams', 'd': 'd. Lightweight construction support system', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Lightweight construction support system'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following can be the result of rapidly cooling cast iron with water?', 'a': 'a. It may gain tensile strength.', 'b': 'b. It may lose small portions from the surface.', 'c': 'c. It may elongate as much as 4 inches 100 mm.', 'd': 'd. It may crack or shatter.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: It may crack or shatter.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Additions to the structure, replacing fire escapes with enclosed stairways, and removing non-load-bearing walls are all types of:', 'a': 'a. security measures.', 'b': 'b. permitted structural modifications.', 'c': 'c. nonpermitted structural modifications.', 'd': 'd. roof obstructions.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: permitted structural modifications.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'How much is added to the weight of floors for every U.S. gallon SI liter used during suppression?', 'a': 'a. 8.33 pounds 3.69 kilograms', 'b': 'b. 10.22 pounds 4.63 kilograms', 'c': 'c. 6.25 pounds 2.83 kilograms', 'd': 'd. 5.22 pounds 2.37 kilograms', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: 8.33 pounds 3.69 kilograms'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'When a collapse is imminent, personnel ___ in the collapse zone.', 'a': 'a. are allowed to work', 'b': 'b. may cautiously place an unstaffed master stream', 'c': 'c. should never work', 'd': 'd. may stay for twenty minutes', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: may cautiously place an unstaffed master stream'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': "Which of the following BEST describes who determines a structure's construction classification type?", 'a': 'a. City official, property owner, contractor', 'b': 'b. Contractor, architect, city official', 'c': 'c. Structural engineer, contractor, city official', 'd': 'd. Architect, structural engineer, contractor', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Architect, structural engineer, contractor'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'The locations of bathrooms and mechanical spaces can be indicated by roof:', 'a': 'a. penetrations and openings.', 'b': 'b. coverings.', 'c': 'c. supports.', 'd': 'd. decks.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: penetrations and openings.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'The critical temperature for steel trusses is:', 'a': 'a. 900°F 482°C.', 'b': 'b. 300°F 149°C.', 'c': 'c. 500°F 260°C.', 'd': 'd. 1,000°F 538°C .', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: 1,000°F 538°C .'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following building materials absorbs heat as moisture evaporates?', 'a': 'a. Metal', 'b': 'b. Gypsum', 'c': 'c. Lath and plaster', 'd': 'd. Reinforced concrete', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Gypsum'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Doors are classified by:', 'a': 'a. where they are located in a structure.', 'b': 'b. what material they are made of.', 'c': 'c. the way they operate.', 'd': 'd. who the original designer was.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: the way they operate.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following movable windows includes a large number of narrow overlapping glass sections that swing outward?', 'a': 'a. Jalousie', 'b': 'b. Awning', 'c': 'c. Pivoting', 'd': 'd. Projecting', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Jalousie'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of roof contains panels that retain electricity even when off?', 'a': 'a. Green roof', 'b': 'b. Rain roof', 'c': 'c. Photovoltaic Solar roof', 'd': 'd. Cold roof', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Photovoltaic Solar roof'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Green wood has a high ___ that affects burn rate.', 'a': 'a. moisture content', 'b': 'b. spalling point', 'c': 'c. failure temperature', 'd': 'd. heat resistance', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: moisture content'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'The interior elements in what type of construction are made of solid or laminated wood with no concealed space?', 'a': 'a. Type III', 'b': 'b. Type II', 'c': 'c. Type IV', 'd': 'd. Type V', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Type IV'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following construction types has walls, floors, and ceilings that must be able to resist fire for three to four hours?', 'a': 'a. Type IV', 'b': 'b. Type V', 'c': 'c. Type I', 'd': 'd. Type III', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Type I'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following must be considered when deciding the size of a collapse zone?', 'a': 'a. Number of personnel on-scene', 'b': 'b. Type of building construction and safest location for personnel', 'c': 'c. Number of personnel on-scene and type of building construction', 'd': 'd. Local adopted building codes', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Type of building construction and safest location for personnel'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Renovation, age of the structure, weather, and loads are all:', 'a': 'a. renovations hazards.', 'b': 'b. building construction hazards.', 'c': 'c. impossible to estimate the impact of on a structure.', 'd': 'd. structural collapse factors.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: structural collapse factors.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of common building material includes bricks, stones, and concrete blocks?', 'a': 'a. Masonry', 'b': 'b. Wood', 'c': 'c. Lath and Plaster', 'd': 'd. Metal', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Masonry'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes walls that support the weight of a structure or structural components?', 'a': 'a. Penetrating walls', 'b': 'b. Fire walls', 'c': 'c. Load-bearing walls', 'd': 'd. Non-load-bearing walls', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Load-bearing walls'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'The critical temperature for steel can be reached at ceiling level from:', 'a': 'a. the rising heat and smoke in the room.', 'b': 'b. heat from other spaces in the structure.', 'c': 'c. the steam from fire suppression efforts.', 'd': 'd. construction materials that burn quickly.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: the rising heat and smoke in the room.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'When exposed to temperatures above ___ unprotected steel will expand and twist.', 'a': 'a. 1,000°F 538°C', 'b': 'b. 900°F 482°C', 'c': 'c. 500°F 260°C', 'd': 'd. 300°F 149°C', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: 1,000°F 538°C'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following buildings may be exempt from local building codes?', 'a': 'a. Factory-built mobile homes', 'b': 'b. School buildings', 'c': 'c. Industrial factories', 'd': 'd. Business structures', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Factory-built mobile homes'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'In which roof style does the design depend on exterior walls to support its weight?', 'a': 'a. Arched', 'b': 'b. Flat', 'c': 'c. Sawtooth', 'd': 'd. Pitched', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Arched'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes where the collapse zone is established?', 'a': 'a. Near any area that is 10 feet 3.04 m from exterior walls', 'b': 'b. Near any area that is 20 feet 6.09 m from exterior walls', 'c': 'c. Adjacent to any exposed interior walls', 'd': 'd. Adjacent to any exposed exterior walls', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Adjacent to any exposed exterior walls'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'For which type of construction is flying glass the primary collapse zone hazard concern?', 'a': 'a. Type I', 'b': 'b. Type V', 'c': 'c. Type III', 'd': 'd. Type IV', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Type I'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of stairs typically connects no more than two levels if not required as part of the means of egress?', 'a': 'a. Protected stairs', 'b': 'b. Exterior stairs', 'c': 'c. Access stairs', 'd': 'd. Unprotected stairs', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Access stairs'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What building component is designed to provide drainage, support snow accumulation, and resist the effects of wind?', 'a': 'a. Floor/Ceiling', 'b': 'b. Wall', 'c': 'c. Foundation', 'd': 'd. Roof', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Roof'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What building component may be an assembly of studs with exterior materials on the outside and an interior covering on the inside?', 'a': 'a. Floor/Ceiling', 'b': 'b. Roof', 'c': 'c. Wall', 'd': 'd. Foundation', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Wall'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What part of the roof extends from wall to wall on a flat roof?', 'a': 'a. Top and bottom chords', 'b': 'b. Horizontal joists', 'c': 'c. Beams', 'd': 'd. Webbing', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Beams'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What type of movable window has a side-hinged sash, usually installed to swing outward?', 'a': 'a. Horizontal sliding', 'b': 'b. Double-hung', 'c': 'c. Single-hung', 'd': 'd. Casement', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Casement'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What building component may be mounted over doors and windows to prevent illegal entry?', 'a': 'a. Solar energy panels', 'b': 'b. Plywood sheathings', 'c': 'c. Security bars or grilles', 'd': 'd. Truss assemblies', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Security bars or grilles'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes a possible construction hazard?', 'a': 'a. Fire detection systems may be damaged.', 'b': 'b. The building is subject to rapid fire spread because protective features are not in place.', 'c': 'c. Danger increases because occupants and belongings remain in one part of the building while work goes on in the other.', 'd': 'd. Furnishings may contribute to fire spread.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: The building is subject to rapid fire spread because protective features are not in place.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What construction type is composed of materials that will not contribute to fire development or spread?', 'a': 'a. Type IV', 'b': 'b. Type I', 'c': 'c. Type III', 'd': 'd. Type II', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Type II'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Knowing types of doors and door hardware can help firefighters:', 'a': 'a. judge roof safety.', 'b': 'b. select the right type of vertical tactical ventilation.', 'c': 'c. predict fire development.', 'd': 'd. select correct forcible entry tools.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: select correct forcible entry tools.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What part of the window is composed of a sill, side jamb, and head jamb?', 'a': 'a. Frame', 'b': 'b. Sash', 'c': 'c. Head', 'd': 'd. Pane', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Frame'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'The use of prefabricated wood truss systems in Type V construction creates:', 'a': 'a. small openings for crawl spaces.', 'b': 'b. a closed channel system between floors.', 'c': 'c. holes for utility lines.', 'd': 'd. a large, open void between floors.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: a large, open void between floors.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'A collapse zone must be established when:', 'a': 'a. there is no evidence of structural instability.', 'b': 'b. mortar between masonry shows no sign of deterioration.', 'c': 'c. furnishings and finishes do not overwhelm fire suppression systems.', 'd': 'd. a defensive strategy has been adopted.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: a defensive strategy has been adopted.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What is the most effective defense against heavy content fuel loading?', 'a': 'a. Adopting local standards that limit multistory buildings', 'b': 'b. Not allowing the use of combustible materials in construction', 'c': 'c. Restricting the types of combustible materials used', 'd': 'd. Proper inspection and code enforcement', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Proper inspection and code enforcement'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following doors has the advantage of eliminating door swing that might interfere with use of interior space?', 'a': 'a. Folding door', 'b': 'b. Revolving door', 'c': 'c. Vertical door', 'd': 'd. Sliding door', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Sliding door'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'What building component is designed to support the weight of a building and all its contents?', 'a': 'a. Floor/Ceiling', 'b': 'b. Wall', 'c': 'c. Roof', 'd': 'd. Foundation', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Foundation'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 4', 'question': 'Which of the following is the most common building material in North America?', 'a': 'a. Lath and Plaster', 'b': 'b. Wood', 'c': 'c. Metal', 'd': 'd. Masonry', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Wood'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What heat transfer method usually occurs through movement of hot smoke and fire gases?', 'a': 'a. Conduction', 'b': 'b. Convection', 'c': 'c. Potential', 'd': 'd. Radiation', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Convection'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What method of heat transfer occurs when a material is heated as the result of direct contact with a heat source?', 'a': 'a. Radiation', 'b': 'b. Conduction', 'c': 'c. Convection', 'd': 'd. Potential', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Conduction'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Liquids with a specific gravity of less than 1 will:', 'a': 'a. turn into vapor.', 'b': 'b. sink below the surface.', 'c': 'c. turn into solid.', 'd': 'd. float on the surface.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: float on the surface.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following terms is the total amount of energy released when a specific amount of fuel is burned?', 'a': 'a. Heat of combustion', 'b': 'b. Heat release rate', 'c': 'c. Thermal energy', 'd': 'd. Chemical energy', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Heat of combustion'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following affects the amount of air entrained in the plume during the growth stage?', 'a': 'a. Thermal layering', 'b': 'b. Location of ignition', 'c': 'c. Type of fuel', 'd': 'd. Location of fuel package', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Location of fuel package'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What thermal property of a compartment contains heat within the compartment, causing localized increase in temperature?', 'a': 'a. Retention', 'b': 'b. Passive agents', 'c': 'c. Heat reflectivity', 'd': 'd. Insulation', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Insulation'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What is the most common form of ignition?', 'a': 'a. Piloted', 'b': 'b. Endothermic', 'c': 'c. Autoignition', 'd': 'd. Exothermic', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Piloted'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Isolated flames in the gas layer during the growth stage indicates:', 'a': 'a. hot and cool gases are mixing together.', 'b': 'b. the temperature is only slightly above ambient.', 'c': 'c. the concentration of combustion products is low.', 'd': 'd. that portions of the layer are within flammable range.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: that portions of the layer are within flammable range.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following sources of energy is a form of oxidation?', 'a': 'a. Sparking', 'b': 'b. Self-heating', 'c': 'c. Spontaneous ignition', 'd': 'd. Resistance heating', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Self-heating'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'The neutral plane in the growth stage is the:', 'a': 'a. point where thermal layering begins.', 'b': 'b. interface of hot and cool layers at an opening.', 'c': 'c. beginning of rapid transition layers.', 'd': 'd. opening in the hot and cool layers.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: interface of hot and cool layers at an opening.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Heat release rate is usually expressed in which of the following measurements?', 'a': 'a. Kilowatts kW', 'b': 'b. Kilojoules/gram kJ/g', 'c': 'c. Kilowatts per meter squared kW/m2', 'd': 'd. British thermal unit Btu', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Kilowatts kW'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following is a heat indicator of a possible flashover?', 'a': 'a. Darkening smoke', 'b': 'b. High velocity and turbulent air flow', 'c': 'c. Bi-directional movement in smoke', 'd': 'd. Darkened windows', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Darkened windows'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What fire stage occurs as the fuel is consumed and oxygen concentration falls?', 'a': 'a. Incipient', 'b': 'b. Fully Developed', 'c': 'c. Growth', 'd': 'd. Decay', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Decay'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': "What type of combustion occurs when burning is localized on or near a fuel's surface?", 'a': 'a. Exothermic', 'b': 'b. Endothermic', 'c': 'c. Flaming', 'd': 'd. Nonflaming', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Nonflaming'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What fire development factor includes cold temperature, strong winds, and wind direction?', 'a': 'a. Fuel type', 'b': 'b. Ambient conditions', 'c': 'c. Availability and location of additional fuel', 'd': 'd. Compartment volume and ceiling height', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Ambient conditions'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What product of combustion is the most common product in structure fires?', 'a': 'a. Hydrogen cyanide', 'b': 'b. Toxic smoke', 'c': 'c. Carbon monoxide', 'd': 'd. Thermal energy', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Carbon monoxide'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What are the elements necessary to create fire in the model represented by the fire triangle?', 'a': 'a. Fuel, oxygen, heat', 'b': 'b. Passive agents and heat', 'c': 'c. Oxygen and passive agents', 'd': 'd. Heat, fuel, ignition', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fuel, oxygen, heat'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes the influence of exposed surfaces on radiant heat?', 'a': 'a. Creating a vacuum will stop radiant     heat.', 'b': 'b. Dark materials emit and absorb heat more effectively than light materials.', 'c': 'c. Temperature differences between the heat source and exposed surface have no impact.', 'd': 'd. Materials that reflect radiated energy help increase radiant heat.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Dark materials emit and absorb heat more effectively than light materials.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes the impact of an extinguishing agent when trying to extinguish flaming combustion?', 'a': 'a. It forms an unstable product.', 'b': 'b. It burns more oxygen in a short amount of time.', 'c': 'c. It interferes with the chemical reaction.', 'd': 'd. It speeds the combustion reaction.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: It interferes with the chemical reaction.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes the impact of higher oxygen concentration on combustion?', 'a': 'a. Materials burn more intensely.', 'b': 'b. Nonflaming combustion is extinguished.', 'c': 'c. Materials that do not burn at normal levels still do not burn.', 'd': 'd. Fires may be easier to extinguish.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Materials burn more intensely.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes what the fire tetrahedron represents?', 'a': 'a. The process of autoignition', 'b': 'b. An uninhibited chemical chain reaction', 'c': 'c. A transfer of sound energy', 'd': 'd. The relationship between fuel, oxygen, heat', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: An uninhibited chemical chain reaction'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'The energy possessed by a moving object is called:', 'a': 'a. thermal energy.', 'b': 'b. potential energy.', 'c': 'c. kinetic energy.', 'd': 'd. mechanical energy.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: kinetic energy.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which type of fuel does not contain carbon?', 'a': 'a. Reactive', 'b': 'b. Organic', 'c': 'c. Simple', 'd': 'd. Inorganic', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Inorganic'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What product of combustion causes the most fire deaths?', 'a': 'a. Carbon dioxide', 'b': 'b. Toxic smoke', 'c': 'c. Thermal energy', 'd': 'd. Hydrogen cyanide', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Toxic smoke'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes what vapor pressure indicates?', 'a': 'a. What form the substance will take in a container', 'b': 'b. What direction a substance will take when released from a container', 'c': 'c. How easily a substance will evaporate', 'd': 'd. How long it takes a substance to evaporate', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: How easily a substance will evaporate'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What fire behavior can be the result of wind from outside the structure?', 'a': 'a. Oxygen exclusion', 'b': 'b. Chemical flame inhibition', 'c': 'c. Temperature reduction', 'd': 'd. Unplanned ventilation', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Unplanned ventilation'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What fire development factor is based on considering how the volume of air will impact radiated heat in a fire?', 'a': 'a. Fuel type', 'b': 'b. Availability and location of additional fuel', 'c': 'c. Ambient conditions', 'd': 'd. Compartment volume and ceiling height', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Compartment volume and ceiling height'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What fire-suppression method does not work if fuel is self-oxidixing?', 'a': 'a. Temperature reduction', 'b': 'b. Chemical flame inhibition', 'c': 'c. Fuel removal', 'd': 'd. Oxygen exclusion', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Oxygen exclusion'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following terms refers to a substance remaining chemically the same, but changing in size, shape or appearance?', 'a': 'a. Chemical reaction', 'b': 'b. Chemical shift', 'c': 'c. Physical change', 'd': 'd. Parallel alteration', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Physical change'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Fuel particles become smaller as the ratio of surface-to-mass:', 'a': 'a. increases.', 'b': 'b. decreases.', 'c': 'c. stays constant.', 'd': 'd. fluctuates back and forth.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: increases.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What form of compartment fire is controlled by the availability of oxygen and the configuration of fuel?', 'a': 'a. Uncontrolled', 'b': 'b. Fuel-controlled', 'c': 'c. Base controlled', 'd': 'd. Ventilation-controlled', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fuel-controlled'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What is the most common method used in fire fighting operations?', 'a': 'a. Temperature reduction', 'b': 'b. Fuel removal', 'c': 'c. Chemical flame inhibition', 'd': 'd. Oxygen exclusion', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Temperature reduction'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'The primary oxidizing agent in most fires is:', 'a': 'a. oxygen.', 'b': 'b. carbon.', 'c': 'c. nitrogen.', 'd': 'd. hydrogen.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: oxygen.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'The ignition of unburned fire gases at the top of the compartment is known as:', 'a': 'a. flashover.', 'b': 'b. combustion.', 'c': 'c. rollover.', 'd': 'd. smoke explosion.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: rollover.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of rapid fire development occurs as unburned fuel gases contact an ignition source?', 'a': 'a. Smoke explosion', 'b': 'b. Combustion', 'c': 'c. Backdraft', 'd': 'd. Rollover', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Smoke explosion'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes why firefighters must use SCBA during overhaul?', 'a': 'a. Volume and density of smoke may be reduced, but the hazard is not eliminated.', 'b': 'b. Hazardous concentrations of smoke are only present outside the structure.', 'c': 'c. Smoke is not like other flammable gases; it will not burn or explode.', 'd': 'd. Hazardous concentrations are typically below short-term exposure limits.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Volume and density of smoke may be reduced, but the hazard is not eliminated.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following terms is the minimum temperature at which a liquid gives off sufficient vapors to ignite, but still not sustain combustion?', 'a': 'a. Pressure point', 'b': 'b. Flash point', 'c': 'c. Vapor point', 'd': 'd. Fire point', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Flash point'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes how understanding the physical science of fire can help firefighters?', 'a': 'a. It keeps flaming combustion from beginning.', 'b': 'b. It helps in stopping rapid fire behavior from developing.', 'c': 'c. It translates into practical knowledge of fire behavior.', 'd': 'd. It keeps radiant heat from igniting fuel.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: It translates into practical knowledge of fire behavior.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of fuel has mass and volume but no definite shape?', 'a': 'a. Solid', 'b': 'b. Gaseous', 'c': 'c. Chemical', 'd': 'd. Liquid', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Liquid'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What stage of fire development occurs when all the combustible materials in a compartment are burning?', 'a': 'a. Decay', 'b': 'b. Incipient', 'c': 'c. Growth', 'd': 'd. Fully Developed', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fully Developed'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What method of electrical energy occurs when a high-temperature luminous discharge crosses a gap?', 'a': 'a. Overcurrent', 'b': 'b. Arcing', 'c': 'c. Resistance heating', 'd': 'd. Sparking', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Arcing'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What method of heat transfer can become the dominant mode as the fire grows in size?', 'a': 'a. Potential', 'b': 'b. Conduction', 'c': 'c. Convection', 'd': 'd. Radiation', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Radiation'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following represents the amount of energy that an object can release in the future?', 'a': 'a. Kinetic', 'b': 'b. Potential', 'c': 'c. Thermal', 'd': 'd. Mechanical', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Potential'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Water is converted to steam at:', 'a': 'a. 212°F 100°C.', 'b': 'b. 300°F 149°C.', 'c': 'c. 230°F 110°C.', 'd': 'd. 190°F 88 °C.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: 212°F 100°C.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What source of thermal energy is the most common source of heat in combustion reactions?', 'a': 'a. Mechanical energy', 'b': 'b. Electrical energy', 'c': 'c. Radiant energy', 'd': 'd. Chemical energy', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Chemical energy'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'In what stage is fire development largely dependent on the characteristics and configuration of the fuel involved?', 'a': 'a. Incipient', 'b': 'b. Growth', 'c': 'c. Decay', 'd': 'd. Fully Developed', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Incipient'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What term defines the minimum concentration of fuel vapor and air that supports combustion?', 'a': 'a. Upper flammable limit', 'b': 'b. Lower flammable limit', 'c': 'c. Vapor pressure', 'd': 'd. Vaporization', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Lower flammable limit'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of fuel has a definite size and shape?', 'a': 'a. Chemical', 'b': 'b. Gaseous', 'c': 'c. Solid', 'd': 'd. Liquid', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Solid'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following is a heat indicator for a possible backdraft?', 'a': 'a. Contents with high heat release rate', 'b': 'b. Turbulent smoke discharge', 'c': 'c. Fire confined to a void space', 'd': 'd. Smoke stained windows', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Smoke stained windows'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of reaction absorbs energy as it occurs?', 'a': 'a. Kinetic', 'b': 'b. Exothermic', 'c': 'c. Endothermic', 'd': 'd. Potential', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Endothermic'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of fuel can be the most dangerous of all the types?', 'a': 'a. Solid', 'b': 'b. Chemical', 'c': 'c. Gaseous', 'd': 'd. Liquid', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Gaseous'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of reaction releases energy in the form of heat and sometimes light?', 'a': 'a. Potential', 'b': 'b. Endothermic', 'c': 'c. Exothermic', 'd': 'd. Kinetic', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Exothermic'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following is a building indicator for a possible backdraft?', 'a': 'a. Turbulent smoke discharge', 'b': 'b. Little or no visible flame', 'c': 'c. Optically dense smoke', 'd': 'd. Fire confined to a void space', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fire confined to a void space'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What method of fire suppression is the simplest?', 'a': 'a. Oxygen exclusion', 'b': 'b. Fuel removal', 'c': 'c. Chemical flame inhibition', 'd': 'd. Temperature reduction', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fuel removal'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'The process of ignition causes pyrolysis in solid fuels and ___ in liquid fuels.', 'a': 'a. freezing', 'b': 'b. kinetic reaction', 'c': 'c. melting', 'd': 'd. vaporization', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: vaporization'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following is defined as the tendency of gases to form into layers according to temperature?', 'a': 'a. Thermal layering', 'b': 'b. Location of ignition', 'c': 'c. Type of fuel', 'd': 'd. Location of fuel package', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Thermal layering'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What common element of flashover represents the shift from growth stage to fully developed stage?', 'a': 'a. Compartment', 'b': 'b. Rapidity', 'c': 'c. Transition in fire development', 'd': 'd. Ignition of all exposed surfaces', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Transition in fire development'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What term is used to describe the extent to which a substance will mix with water?', 'a': 'a. Reactivity', 'b': 'b. Solubility', 'c': 'c. Volatility', 'd': 'd. Mixability', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Solubility'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'In what mode of combustion is a visible flame produced?', 'a': 'a. Nonflaming', 'b': 'b. Kinetic', 'c': 'c. Potential', 'd': 'd. Flaming', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Flaming'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What suppression method uses extinguishing agents to stop flame production?', 'a': 'a. Ventilation', 'b': 'b. Oxygen exclusion', 'c': 'c. Temperature reduction', 'd': 'd. Chemical flame inhibition', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Chemical flame inhibition'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What type of rapid fire development happens when all the combustible materials and gases in a compartment ignite almost simultaneously?', 'a': 'a. Flashover', 'b': 'b. Smoke explosion', 'c': 'c. Backdraft', 'd': 'd. Combustion', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Flashover'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': "What mode of combustion produces a smoldering glow in a material's surface?", 'a': 'a. Potential', 'b': 'b. Flaming', 'c': 'c. Nonflaming', 'd': 'd. Kinetic', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Nonflaming'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes kinetic energy transfer?', 'a': 'a. It moves from high-temperature to low-temperature substances.', 'b': 'b. It moves from low-temperature to high-temperature substances.', 'c': 'c. It does not move at all.', 'd': 'd. It moves from one substance to another, no matter what the temperature.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: It moves from high-temperature to low-temperature substances.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following terms is used to refer to the process that can generate sufficient quantities of burnable vapors to ignite in the presence of a sufficient oxidizer?', 'a': 'a. Fire point', 'b': 'b. Vapor pressure', 'c': 'c. Flash point', 'd': 'd. Pyrolysis', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Pyrolysis'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'The potential chemical energy of fuel in fire behavior is converted to:', 'a': 'a. thermal energy.', 'b': 'b. mechanical energy.', 'c': 'c. electrical energy.', 'd': 'd. sound energy.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: thermal energy.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following fire development factors affects heat release rate?', 'a': 'a. Ventilation', 'b': 'b. Availability and location of additional fuel', 'c': 'c. Fuel type', 'd': 'd. Compartment volume and ceiling height', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fuel type'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'When a substance changes from one type of matter to another, it has had a:', 'a': 'a. physical change.', 'b': 'b. chemical reaction.', 'c': 'c. chemical shift.', 'd': 'd. physical alteration.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: chemical reaction.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What aspect of fire development is a result of an increase in low-level ventilation prior to upper level ventilation?', 'a': 'a. Combustion', 'b': 'b. Backdraft', 'c': 'c. Smoke explosion', 'd': 'd. Rollover', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Backdraft'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'What product of combustion may heat adjacent fuels, making them susceptible to ignition?', 'a': 'a. Thermal energy', 'b': 'b. Carbon monoxide', 'c': 'c. Hydrogen cyanide', 'd': 'd. Toxic smoke', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Thermal energy'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 5', 'question': 'Which of the following BEST describes the complete oxidation of methane?', 'a': 'a. It produces carbon dioxide and water.', 'b': 'b. It produces oxygen and water.', 'c': 'c. It produces carbon dioxide.', 'd': 'd. It produces water.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: It produces carbon dioxide and water.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Do not remove the safety pin on a portable fire extinguisher until:', 'a': 'a. ordered to by the commanding officer.', 'b': 'b. the fire appears to be dying out.', 'c': 'c. ready to use the extinguisher.', 'd': 'd. you are 10 feet 3.04 meters from the fire.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: ready to use the extinguisher.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'The P in the PASS acronym stands for:', 'a': 'a. pull pin by breaking wire or seal.', 'b': 'b. squeeze handles.', 'c': 'c. aim nozzle at base of fire.', 'd': 'd. sweep nozzle back and forth.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: pull pin by breaking wire or seal.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What portable fire extinguisher rating is based on the approximate square foot square meter area of flammable liquid a nonexpert operator can extinguish?', 'a': 'a. Class K rating', 'b': 'b. Multiple markings', 'c': 'c. Class B rating', 'd': 'd. Class A rating', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Class B rating'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'The resulting foam from an aqueous film forming foam AFFF extinguisher will ___ fuels lighter than water.', 'a': 'a. sink below the surface of', 'b': 'b. cause a chemical reaction with', 'c': 'c. float on the surface of', 'd': 'd. mix in with', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: float on the surface of'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What type of portable fire extinguisher is intended for use on Class K fires?', 'a': 'a. Clean agent', 'b': 'b. Aqueous film forming foam', 'c': 'c. Pump-type water', 'd': 'd. Wet chemical stored-pressure', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Wet chemical stored-pressure'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What application method is used with an aqueous film forming foam AFFF extinguisher in order to prevent disturbing the fuel?', 'a': 'a. Allow foam to gently rain down onto fuel surface', 'b': 'b. Apply foam in conjunction with dry ice crystals', 'c': 'c. Apply foam directly to fuel surface', 'd': 'd. Allow foam to rest before applying to fuel surface', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Allow foam to gently rain down onto fuel surface'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What classification of portable fire extinguisher is used on fires that involve combustible cooking oils?', 'a': 'a. Class K', 'b': 'b. Class A', 'c': 'c. Class B', 'd': 'd. Class D', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Class K'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Which of the following statements BEST describes how to prevent scattering of lightweight fuels?', 'a': 'a. Use two extinguishers, alternating application patterns, to apply agent to the fuel surface.', 'b': 'b. Apply the agent from point where it reaches, but does not disturb, the fuel surface.', 'c': 'c. First allow fuel to burn off vapors before applying agent to the fuel surface.', 'd': 'd. Wind may be used to allow the agent to reach the fuel surface.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Apply the agent from point where it reaches, but does not disturb, the fuel surface.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What classification of portable fire extinguisher is used for fires that involve combustible liquids and gases?', 'a': 'a. Class B', 'b': 'b. Class A', 'c': 'c. Class D', 'd': 'd. Class K', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Class B'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What portable fire extinguisher rating considers both the toxicity of the extinguishing agent and the toxicity of fumes produced when the agent is applied?', 'a': 'a. Class C rating', 'b': 'b. Class A rating', 'c': 'c. Class D rating', 'd': 'd. Class B rating', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Class D rating'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'NFPA® 10 requires inspection of portable fire extinguishers at least:', 'a': 'a. every three months.', 'b': 'b. once every six months.', 'c': 'c. after every use.', 'd': 'd. once a year.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: once a year.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What type of portable fire extinguisher is discharged in the form of gas and works on Class B and Class C fires?', 'a': 'a. Wet chemical stored-pressure', 'b': 'b. Clean agent', 'c': 'c. Carbon dioxide CO2', 'd': 'd. Pump-type water', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Carbon dioxide CO2'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Once the proper extinguisher is selected, you must check to ensure the pressure gauge:', 'a': 'a. records the last maintenance performed.', 'b': 'b. is not clouded over.', 'c': 'c. is in the operable range.', 'd': 'd. has been properly inspected.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: is in the operable range.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Which method of extinguishing works by excluding oxygen from the burning process?', 'a': 'a. Cooling', 'b': 'b. Saponification', 'c': 'c. Smothering', 'd': 'd. Chain breaking', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Smothering'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'How often should portable fire extinguishers be removed from service for maintenance?', 'a': 'a. Annually', 'b': 'b. Bi-monthly', 'c': 'c. Monthly', 'd': 'd. Bi-annually', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Annually'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What classification of portable fire extinguisher is used for fires that involve combustible metals and alloys?', 'a': 'a. Class K', 'b': 'b. Class A', 'c': 'c. Class D', 'd': 'd. Class B', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Class D'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What type of portable fire extinguisher is intended primarily for ground cover fires?', 'a': 'a. Aqueous film forming foam', 'b': 'b. Wet chemical stored-pressure', 'c': 'c. Pump-type water', 'd': 'd. Clean agent', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Pump-type water'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'During inspection, if a portable fire extinguisher is found deficient in weight by ___ percent it should be removed from service and replaced.', 'a': 'a. 5', 'b': 'b. 10', 'c': 'c. 8', 'd': 'd. 12', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: 10'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What type of portable fire extinguisher uses air stored in the tank to force water up a siphon tube when operated?', 'a': 'a. Carbon dioxide CO2', 'b': 'b. Clean agent', 'c': 'c. Stored-pressure water', 'd': 'd. Pump-type water', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Stored-pressure water'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Once the proper extinguisher is selected, you must perform a visual inspection to ensure the extinguisher:', 'a': 'a. feels as though it contains agent.', 'b': 'b. has a long enough hose to reach the fire.', 'c': 'c. has no external marks.', 'd': 'd. is charged and operable.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: is charged and operable.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Portable fire extinguishers should be chosen based on the:', 'a': 'a. type of fuel that is burning.', 'b': 'b. amount of agent required to extinguish the fire.', 'c': 'c. heat of the fire.', 'd': 'd. distance required between the extinguisher and the fire.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: type of fuel that is burning.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What expelling mechanism works when the operator physically applies pressure to a pump that increases pressure within the container?', 'a': 'a. Stored pressure', 'b': 'b. Manual pump', 'c': 'c. Scoop', 'd': 'd. Pressure cartridge', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Manual pump'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Signal to others that a portable fire extinguisher is empty by:', 'a': 'a. marking it with a tag.', 'b': 'b. laying it on its side.', 'c': 'c. covering the hose with a blanket.', 'd': 'd. standing it straight up.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: laying it on its side.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'On a multiple marking extinguisher the ratings for each class are:', 'a': 'a. only identified by pictographs.', 'b': 'b. directly related to the others.', 'c': 'c. indicators that firefighters should not use them.', 'd': 'd. separate, they do not affect each other.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: separate, they do not affect each other.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What type of portable fire extinguisher may be applied with either an extinguisher or a scoop?', 'a': 'a. Wet chemical stored-pressure', 'b': 'b. Dry powder', 'c': 'c. Dry chemical', 'd': 'd. Pump-type water', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Dry powder'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'What type of portable fire extinguisher may produce a cloud that reduces visibility when discharged?', 'a': 'a. Wet chemical stored-pressure', 'b': 'b. Aqueous film forming foam', 'c': 'c. Dry chemical', 'd': 'd. Pump-type water', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Dry chemical'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 7', 'question': 'Which statement BEST describes portable fire extinguisher selection?', 'a': 'a. The correct extinguisher will minimize risk to life and property.', 'b': 'b. Extinguisher ratings do not impact selection.', 'c': 'c. The correct extinguisher will always require an expert operator.', 'd': 'd. All types of extinguishers can be selected regardless of the situation.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: The correct extinguisher will minimize risk to life and property.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Storing rope in a bag can make it easy to transport and protects it from:', 'a': 'a. contamination.', 'b': 'b. direct heat.', 'c': 'c. moisture in the air.', 'd': 'd. gasoline fumes.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: contamination.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'When the sheath of a braid-on-braid rope slides on its core, a fire fighter should:', 'a': 'a. record the damage in the rope log.', 'b': 'b. cut off the end to pull off excess material.', 'c': 'c. store the rope in a dryer place, moisture is causing the slippage.', 'd': 'd. destroy the rope immediately.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: cut off the end to pull off excess material.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'What emergency scene use for rope can help provide a physical means of finding an exit route?', 'a': 'a. Control zone perimeter', 'b': 'b. Search lines', 'c': 'c. Object stabilization', 'd': 'd. Tool hoisting', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Search lines'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following types of rope may not elongate more than 10 percent under a load equal to 10 percent of its breaking strength?', 'a': 'a. Static kernmantle rope', 'b': 'b. Dynamic kernmantle rope', 'c': 'c. Laid rope', 'd': 'd. Braided rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Static kernmantle rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which type of knot can be used as a stopper knot so rope will not pass through a rescue pulley?', 'a': 'a. Bowline', 'b': 'b. Handcuff', 'c': 'c. Figure-eight', 'd': 'd. Becket bend', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Figure-eight'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'In a kernmantle rope, the _____ protects the core from abrasion.', 'a': 'a. sheath', 'b': 'b. low stretch fiber', 'c': 'c. overlapping strand', 'd': 'd. twisted fiber', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: sheath'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following types of rope is intended for self-rescue situations?', 'a': 'a. Utility rope', 'b': 'b. Life safety rope', 'c': 'c. Escape rope', 'd': 'd. Water rescue rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Escape rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following types of rope is constructed of a braided core enclosed in a braided, herringbone-pattern sheath?', 'a': 'a. Dynamic kernmantle rope', 'b': 'b. Braided rope', 'c': 'c. Static kernmantle rope', 'd': 'd. Braid-on-braid rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Braid-on-braid rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'What type of damage must be recorded in the rope log because it cannot be detected by inspections?', 'a': 'a. Impact loading incidents', 'b': 'b. Exposure to chemical vapors', 'c': 'c. Exposure to direct flame', 'd': 'd. Sustained load incidents', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Impact loading incidents'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': "Which type of knot can be used to secure a victim's hands or feet to drag the victim to safety?", 'a': 'a. Handcuff', 'b': 'b. Becket bend', 'c': 'c. Bowline', 'd': 'd. Figure-eight', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Handcuff'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following types of rope is the only rope required to have a rope log?', 'a': 'a. Escape rope', 'b': 'b. Water rescue rope', 'c': 'c. Life safety rope', 'd': 'd. Utility rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Life safety rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'For which of the following types of rope are soft spots possible signs of damage to the core?', 'a': 'a. Kernmantle rope', 'b': 'b. Braid-on-braid rope', 'c': 'c. Laid rope', 'd': 'd. Braided rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Kernmantle rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following is an advantage of synthetic fiber rope?', 'a': 'a. Very strong yet lightweight', 'b': 'b. Resistant to sunlight', 'c': 'c. Does not melt when exposed to heat', 'd': 'd. Holds a knot firmly', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Very strong yet lightweight'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'What type of webbing is mainly used for rescue applications?', 'a': 'a. Tubular webbing', 'b': 'b. Life safety webbing', 'c': 'c. Flat webbing', 'd': 'd. Utility webbing', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Tubular webbing'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'How often should unused rope be inspected?', 'a': 'a. At least once a year', 'b': 'b. Every month', 'c': 'c. Every six months', 'd': 'd. At least twice a year', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: At least once a year'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which type of knot eliminates the danger of the running end slipping back through the knot?', 'a': 'a. Overhand safety', 'b': 'b. Bowline', 'c': 'c. Handcuff', 'd': 'd. Half-hitch', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Overhand safety'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'During hoisting, which of the following actions is the BEST way to help prevent damage to the equipment?', 'a': 'a. Using the same hoisting method for all types of equipment', 'b': 'b. Hoisting all equipment at once', 'c': 'c. Using proper knots and securing procedures', 'd': 'd. Hoisting SCBA first', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Using proper knots and securing procedures'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Webbing care and maintenance guidelines are:', 'a': 'a. the same as those for synthetic rope.', 'b': 'b. the same as those for life safety rope.', 'c': 'c. the same as those for natural rope.', 'd': 'd. the same as those for kernmantle rope.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: the same as those for synthetic rope.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following types of rope is less likely to twist during use than laid rope?', 'a': 'a. Braid-on-braid rope', 'b': 'b. Braided rope', 'c': 'c. Dynamic kernmantle rope', 'd': 'd. Static kernmantle rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Braided rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following pieces of equipment is best used to provide a mechanical advantage during hoisting?', 'a': 'a. Rope', 'b': 'b. Webbing', 'c': 'c. Carabiner', 'd': 'd. Pulley', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Pulley'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which part of the rope is used for hoisting?', 'a': 'a. Running', 'b': 'b. Knot', 'c': 'c. Standing', 'd': 'd. Working', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Running'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following types of rope is only used in situations not involving life safety?', 'a': 'a. Water rescue rope', 'b': 'b. Life safety rope', 'c': 'c. Escape rope', 'd': 'd. Utility rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Utility rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following are signs of damage in laid natural fiber rope?', 'a': 'a. Abrasions or fuzziness', 'b': 'b. Powdering between strands', 'c': 'c. Irregularities in weave', 'd': 'd. Excessive stretching', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Powdering between strands'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'What type of webbing is rated for loads up to 600 pounds 2.67 k/N and fastens around the waist and thighs or under buttocks?', 'a': 'a. Class II life safety webbing', 'b': 'b. Utility webbing', 'c': 'c. Class III life safety webbing', 'd': 'd. Class I life safety webbing', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Class II life safety webbing'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Firefighters should avoid _____ in order to prevent grinding dirt and debris into ropes.', 'a': 'a. allowing rope to come into contact with chemicals', 'b': 'b. exposing rope to sustained loads', 'c': 'c. exposing rope to rust', 'd': 'd. walking on rope', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: walking on rope'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which part of the rope is used to tie a knot or hitch?', 'a': 'a. Knot', 'b': 'b. Working', 'c': 'c. Running', 'd': 'd. Standing', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Working'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which type of knot is used for joining two ropes of unequal diameter?', 'a': 'a. Bowline', 'b': 'b. Figure-eight', 'c': 'c. Handcuff', 'd': 'd. Becket bend', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Becket bend'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Removing the slack in rope after tying a knot is called:', 'a': 'a. standing.', 'b': 'b. running.', 'c': 'c. working.', 'd': 'd. dressing.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: dressing.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'What type of webbing is mainly used for straps and harness?', 'a': 'a. Flat webbing', 'b': 'b. Tubular webbing', 'c': 'c. Utility webbing', 'd': 'd. Life safety webbing', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Flat webbing'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which bend is formed by bending a rope back on itself while keeping both sides parallel?', 'a': 'a. Loop', 'b': 'b. Round turn', 'c': 'c. Bight', 'd': 'd. Knot', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Bight'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'Which of the following allows the re-use a life safety rope?', 'a': 'a. Passed inspection by qualified personnel', 'b': 'b. Subjected to impact load', 'c': 'c. Abrasions or visible damage', 'd': 'd. Exposed to heat or direct flame', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Passed inspection by qualified personnel'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'What emergency scene use for rope can help prevent a vehicle from falling when suspended over an edge?', 'a': 'a. Control zone perimeter', 'b': 'b. Search lines', 'c': 'c. Object stabilization', 'd': 'd. Tool hoisting', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Object stabilization'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 8', 'question': 'When drying a rope, firefighters should avoid:', 'a': 'a. suspending rope in a hose tower.', 'b': 'b. drying rope in the direct sunlight.', 'c': 'c. spreading out rope on hose drying rack.', 'd': 'd. loosely coiling rope in a hose dryer.', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: drying rope in the direct sunlight.'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 10', 'question': 'Which of the following vehicle extrication hazards can be isolated by deactivating undeployed air bags?', 'a': 'a. Sharp objects', 'b': 'b. Traffic', 'c': 'c. Fire', 'd': 'd. Blood borne pathogens', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Fire'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 10', 'question': 'What type of structural collapse occurs when the floor and/or roof assemblies on both sides of a load-bearing wall collapse, allowing a good chance of victim survival?', 'a': 'a. A-frame', 'b': 'b. V-shaped', 'c': 'c. Pancake', 'd': 'd. Cantilever', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: A-frame'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 10', 'question': 'What initial action is the next priority after stabilizing the scene?', 'a': 'a. Size-up the situation', 'b': 'b. Communicate information', 'c': 'c. Stabilize the victim', 'd': 'd. Establish scene security', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Stabilize the victim'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 10', 'question': 'What type of technical rescue involves physical hazards such as debris that is sharp, jagged, or unstable as well as exposed wiring and rebar?', 'a': 'a. Structural collapse rescue', 'b': 'b. Vehicle rescue', 'c': 'c. Confined-space rescue', 'd': 'd. Water rescue', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Structural collapse rescue'},{'chapter': 'Chapter 10', 'question': 'Which of the following rescue tool uses includes tools to drag materials away to free victims?', 'a': 'a. Cutting', 'b': 'b. Stabilizing', 'c': 'c. Pulling', 'd': 'd. Lifting', 'ans': 'The correct answer is: Pulling'},

]